# William E. {Ted} Glynn III

3069 Tejon St. Unit C Denver, CO 80211 720-429-4570 will.glynn@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/ruxpin86 Portfolio: https://tedglynn.com

Full stack web developer with extensive experience in the service industry at all levels, providing exceptional soft-skills and a customer focused approach to developing responsive web applications. Strong interpersonal skills with respect to leadership and teamwork, as well as realizing projects from inception to completion. Passionate about creating exciting and intuitive user experiences that maintain retention and interest for the entirety of a products life-cycle. Received certification from the University of Denver in Full Stack Web Development and continuing to build and learn daily.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

 HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, NoSQL, Express, MongoDB, GraphQL, Node.js, React, BootStrap, Socket.io, jQuery, Jest, Regex, MERN stack, SERN stack, Git, GitHub, RESTful APIs

## **PROJECTS**

- DU Event Listeners | https://du-event-listeners.heokuapp.com
  - Overview: With bootcamp reaching its conclusion, our team wanted to have a common
    place for alumni to stay connected and be able to share resources and ideas. Upon
    completing login, users have access to shared class resources, community events, a
    questions forum, and live chat feature.
  - Contributions: Front end design, validation, live-chat implementation
  - Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REACT, socket.io, MongoDB, GraphQL, bcrypt, Express, BootStrap
- Almost fAlMous | https://almost-faim-ous.herokuapp.com
  - Overview: For our first full stack web application we decided to create a light-hearted throwback to the original days of instant messaging. With a virtual desktop that harkens back to the days of Windows Vista and the ability to create user accounts and have messages with persistent conversation history.
  - Contributions: Front and Back end JavaScript, implementation of socket.io
  - Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, SQL, Express, Sequelize, Node.js, socket.io
- Everything but the Kitchen Sink | <a href="https://ruxpin86.github.io/home-cooking-app-project-1/">https://ruxpin86.github.io/home-cooking-app-project-1/</a>
  - Overview: This web app offers those having trouble deciding what they would like to cook a quick solution to find recipes based upon what ingredients they have on hand.
  - Contributions: Front end functionality, API linkages and displaying fetch calls
  - Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, BootStrap

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Event Tech Support, Array — February 2021 - Present

Provided support for panel members and participants by ensuring that they were able to interface with the platform, as well as manage Zoom connectivity — Created and responded to support tickets while adhering to company best practices to allow for proper data tracking and trend recognition — Resolved any possible tech issues by providing fast, friendly, and efficient fixes to keep audience members engaged and interacting with data collection tools — Implemented software updates on our hardware for a fleet of 3000 devices as well as maintaining version control to help optimize engineering builds for the platform and ensure a seamless experience for on-site users

# General Manager, Canopy — January 2018 – April 2022

Managed a high volume, fast-paced bar in the center of Denver's Baker neighborhood (even through a once in a century pandemic) — Handled all staff scheduling and training — Maintained proper cash handling and daily accounting practices — Executed all weekly ordering and inventory management — Regularly fixed and maintained bar equipment as well as diagnosing/delegating issues that required outside referrals

## Bartender, Roosevelt — March 2018 – April 2022

Provided high-quality hospitality for customers in a lively environment that requires specialty bartending skills.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Denver, Denver, CO - Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp - Attended April 2022 - *Graduated*: August 2022 (94.82% average)

Southern Connecticut State University, New Haven, CT – Political Science/Economics - Attended August, 2006 – May, 2008

University of Tampa, Tampa, FL – Marine Science/Biology - Attended August, 2004 – May, 2005 Waterford High School, Waterford, CT - Graduated June, 2004